Welcome to another video, so in this video we are going to learn the other tools that
was used for discovery tactics, this is 60% of the time, I have observed in multiple
threat factors, active incidents, the advanced IP scanner, they will be commonly using
this tool for network infrastructure, infrastructure enumerations activity and from this
tool they can understand what was the host was online and what was the host is about,
even the microtrus activity, everything, okay.
So, I have a lot of incident and a lot of cases that was triggered for the advanced IP
scanner activities, let me learn how to detect the flow bridging that legitimate tools
to perform their malicious activity, okay.
So, let me want to the advanced IP scanner download, so once you get on this, just click
on the feed download, it will automatically download the advanced IP scanner into your
launcher and once you download and double click on the advanced IP scanner, it will
install your environment and this is the consuming interface, this is the GUI interface,
you can use it in the console also, we will learn how to do that in the next thing.
And let me show you something, so here you can see, you need to give the proper input
here, if you need to scan the entire host, like entire network, so my gateway will be
starting from, let me show you something, IEPCon, okay, so here I can see my default
data was 192.168.18.1, so I just given the 192.168.18.1 to 254 to scan the entire network,
let me scan this, so it started the scanning, it will be giving the input which host
are offline and which of the host are online and here you can find few more input with
the name Navin and multiple devices, it was showing, so you can see, once the scans get
completed you can save your input by giving the save us and there is much option to explore
in this advanced IP scanner, but it is definitely a good tool to enumerate the network
information, so the host related information, okay, and so as per the contactive activity
they will be using the console also, so once they get on to the mission, they will be executing
the command, so you guys are now familiar with how to handle the mission from the Carlian
X, you can use Smallbin, you can use multiple things, so you have, you are very familiar
how to handle this, so I was showing just an example within a live mission, but if you
are attacking any environment, you will be getting your Carlian X console and you will be
executing from command from that mission, so the GUI output has been completed, so
we can give a save us and you can save the output in these three formats which TML or
CSE has something, okay, so let me cancel this and we will jump on to the console interface,
so this is the path which the advanced IP scanner console was there and I was giving
the range as 192.168. me and edit this range, yes, 18.1, 2, 2, 5, 4 and the file output will
be saving the network.6 instead of that attack, scan attacker, scan.cs, let me execute
this one, it will take some time to complete the scanning, because you can see the GUI
also took some time to scan the environment, the similar way the console will be also
take some time to scan the environment, okay, this is the way how the attack test will
be executing the commands, okay, now it was given the output here, the attacker scan.cs,
let go to the directory and let's see how the scan has been saved, so here you can find
the result, so let, now you can find some alive host and some dead host and some unknown
host type, so these are the host are now alive and let me filter out the live host and
some, so these are some services are running, let's take this, let's store this information
for the future purpose, okay, so let's have this information for future attacks, okay,
so this is how the threat attack will be compromising the account and they will be using
the advanced safety scanner command line in the face to scan the environment and they
will be getting the results like this, okay, so let's hop off this video and we will continue
our topic in the next video. See you guys. Bye bye.